## PRAVEEN KUMAR BOMMU

Email ID: <u>praveenbommu@virtusa.com</u>

Voice: +91 - 9441 146 300

#### **SUMMARY**

Highly skilled software development professional bringing over 5+ years in software development and integration using .NET Core. I am an experienced technical Full-stack Developer who specializes in front-end development with the skill of Angular, and angular js well versed in all the stages of web application development by using Agile and Scrum methodology. I'm ambitious, and hardworking, and want to find a company that I can grow with as I achieve its goals.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : C#, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS and **Bootstrap 5**.

Technical Skills : Angular- 10, .Net Core 6.0, Web API, Oracle PL/SQL, SQL Server,

Ionic, VueJS,React(Basics), NGRX(Basics),Angular JS, MySQL and Node.Js.

Development Frameworks : Scrum/Agile, Entity Framework Core, Swagger, REST API, Kanban

board, Ionic Framework, Cordova and Capacitor.

Scripting Languages : JavaScript, jQuery and TypeScript.

Cloud Services : Cognitive Services, App Services, Azure Function App, and Storage Accounts

Designing Tools : Adobe Photoshop CS3, Adobe Illustrator and Corel VideoStudio.

IDE : Visual Studio, VS Code & Brackets.

Source Code Management : **GitHub, Bitbucket** and DevOps.

Continuous Integration : **Jenkins** and DevOps Pipelines.

Planning & Collaboration : JIRA, Confluence, Slack and Teams.

Unit Testing Tools : MSTest, xUnit, NUnit, **Karma**, Jasmine.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Virtusa Consulting Services**

Hyderabad, Telangana

Senior Lead Software Engineer

Sep 2023 - Present

Technologies on which I have worked over here are .Net Core, Web API, Enterprise Design System Angular 14,Sonar Qube, Entity Framework Core, MS Unit Tests, SQL Server, and Jenkins.

## **Virtusa Consulting Services**

Hyderabad, Telangana

Lead Consultant

June 2022 - Aug 2023

Technologies on which I have worked over here are **.Net Core**, **Web API**, AngularJS, Angular Material, Javascript, JQuery, Entity Framework Core, SQL Server, and Jenkins.

#### **Proarch It Solutions**

Hyderabad, Telangana

Software Engineer

Aug 2019 - June 2022.

Technologies on which I have worked over here are .Net Core, Web API, Angular, AngularJS, Bootstrap 5, TypeScript, Entity Framework Core, Oracle PL/SQL, MySql, and SQL Server.

Software Engineer

Jun 2018 - Jul 2019.

Technologies on which I have worked over here are **NodeJs, Angular**, .Net Core, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap javaScript, jQuery, MySql, MongoDB and UiPath Automation Tool.

### **PROJECTS**

- 1. ICG-Analytics CACRM-API
- **2.** ICG-Analytics ICGCoverage
- **3.** ICG-Analytics CACRM-Jobs
- 4. Meridian (<a href="https://www.meridian.coop/">https://www.meridian.coop/</a>)
- 5. Solcharge (<a href="https://dev.solcharge.com/">https://dev.solcharge.com/</a>)
- 6. Employee Management System Internal project for Proarch employees(<a href="https://ems.proarch.com/">https://ems.proarch.com/</a>).
- 7. AI in Healthcare (https://tranquilminds.com/).
- 8. KnoahsARK 360 (https://login.knoahsark360.com/) IND Internal project for knoah employees.

### RESPONSIBILITIES

- Proficiency in Microsoft ASP.Net Core, C#, Entity Framework Core.
- Leads and coordinates code peer reviews, code branching and merging activities, approval of Git pull requests from developers on the team, does continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD) of code, calibrates unit, coded UI, and performance tests of the applications, deploys and uses code quality tools to ensure code coverage and quality, and manages the promotion of application code from/to the various environments through collaboration with the QA and Scrum teams.
- Prior experience with API Design using API description tools such as Swagger,
- Develop and manage business plans to achieve objectives
- Third-party API integration like SMS, OTP verification, and Social Media Plugins.
- Integration of Google Maps and other Google APIs.
- Excellent knowledge of Object Oriented Principles and design patterns.
- Able to make frontend changes (Angular, Kendo UI, bootstrap UI with Typescript, Javascript and jQuery).
- Deploy, Configure and Maintain Applications on **Azure Cloud**.
- Experienced in all project phases using Waterfall and Agile Methodologies.

## **CERTIFICATES AND RECOGNITIONS**

- Microsoft Azure Developer Associate (AZ-204) certification.
- Robotic Automation Processing foundation certifications (Level 1 to Level 3) from Ui-Path Academy.
- KnowBe4 Social Engineering Reg Flags, Global Privacy and Data Protection.

### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

- B.TECH in Computer Science at VSM College of Engineering, 2018.
- Diploma in Computer Engineering at Dr.BRA GMR Polytechnic College, 2014.
- Secondary School Certificate (SSC) at S.R.G Mpl High School, 2011.

# PERSONAL DETAILS

Mother's name : Vijaya Kumari Bommu

Father's name : Srinivas Bommu

Date of birth : 27<sup>th</sup> Mar 1996

Languages known : English, Telugu, and Hindi

Nationality : INDIAN

Gender : Male

Marital status : Married

Address : Kakinada, Andhra Pradesh, Pin-533 005.

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is accurate to the best of my knowledge.

Ρl	a	c	e	:
PΙ		c	e	

Date: (B.Praveen Kumar)